Guide to the Jesse H. Jones Family and Personal Papers, 1841-2000 MS 252
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Jesse H. Jones Family and Personal Papers
1841-2000
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Jones, Jesse H. (Jesse Holman)
MS 252
52 Linear Feet (94 boxes)
2.73 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0252aip_001 (2.73 GB)
1.53 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0252aip_002 (1.53 GB)
The Jesse H. Jones Family and Personal Papers, consisting of 92 boxes, detail the lives of individual Jones family members and are highlighted by the Jesse H. Jones personal papers consisting of correspondence, photographs, financial, legal, speeches and business records, as well as the political, civic-related and public service records for which Jones is well known.
Biographical / Historical
Jesse Holman Jones, son of William Hasque Jones and Laura Holman Jones, was born in Robertson County, TN, April 5, 1874. The family soon moved to Dallas, TX, where William Jones managed his brother's lumberyard in Terrell. Two years later the family moved to a farm on the Kentucky-Tennessee border, where after completing ninth grade, Jesse was put in charge of one of his father's tobacco factories. In 1891 Jesse entered Hill's Business College in Dallas and then in 1895 started work at his uncle's firm, the M.T. Jones Lumber Co. in Hillsboro, TX. He soon became manager of the Dallas lumberyard, and upon his uncle's death in 1898 became general manager of the Houston yard. He established his own company, the South Texas Lumber Company and expanded into real estate, banking, and commercial buildings and as the largest developer in the area was responsible for most of Houston's prewar construction of over 100 buildings in Houston, Fort Worth, Dallas, New York City. Between 1908 and 1912 he bought part of Houston Chronicle, became chairman of the Texas Trust Company, president of National Bank of Commerce, an original stockholder in Humble Oil and Refining Company, and as chairman of the Houston harbor board, raised money for the Houston Ship Channel.
During World War I President Woodrow Wilson named him director general of military relief for the American Red Cross, he became sole owner of the Houston Chronicle in 1926, and in 1928 as director of finance for the Democratic National Convention, was instrumental in bringing the convention to Houston. President Herbert Hoover named him to the Reconstruction Finance Coporation, President Franklin Roosevelt appointed him head of the RFC (1933-39) and Federal Loan Administrator (1939), and at the same time became Secretary of Commerce. Jones broke his ties with the Democratic party and returned to Houston in 1945 to concentrate on business ventures and philanthropy. Jones died on June 1, 1956.
Scope and Contents
The Jesse H. Jones Family and Personal Papers, consisting of 92 boxes, detail the lives of individual Jones family members and are highlighted by the Jesse H. Jones personal papers consisting of correspondence, photographs, financial, legal, speeches and business records, as well as the political, civic-related and public service records for which Jones is well known. Of interest is Jones' World War II service as Secretary of Commerce and head of the Reconstruction Fianance Corporation, and his involvement with the building of the Houston Ship Channel and the 1928 Democratic National Convention held in Houston. An extensive collection of individual, group, event photographs, and photographs and drawings detailing many of the extant buildings in downtown Houston is included.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was donated by Houston Endowment, Inc. in October 2014.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series, Series I: Family, with sub-series of individual family members, and Series II: Personal (Jesse H. Jones) with sub-series of Life Cycle, Residences, Correspondence, Commemorations, Honors, Personal property, Insurance, Social memberships, Business, Editorials, Political, Public Service, Public Statements, Speeches, Interviews, Civic-related, Photographs, and Realia.
Related Materials
See also Jesse H. Jones Corporate and Property Records, and M.T. Jones Lumber Co. Records & Business Ledgers; Barker Texas History Center, University of Texas at Austin, and Library of Congress. See online exhibit at: http://digitalprojects.rice.edu/wrc/JesseHJones/
Index Terms
Subjects
Business; Social life and customs; Politics and government
Document Types
financial records; letters (correspondence); clippings (information artifacts); photographs; awards; genealogies (histories)
Places
Houston (Tex.) -- History.; Texas -- Houston Ship Channel
Subjects (Persons)
Jones, Jesse H. (Jesse Holman); Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano); Wilson, Woodrow; Rogers, Will; Roosevelt, Elliott
Subjects (Corporations)
Democratic National Convention; Reconstruction Finance Corporation
- Series I: Family, 207785 (Box 1-15)
  - Subseries A: M. Tilford Jones, 207786 (Box 1)
    - Wills, 1897-98; 207787 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Estate, 207788 (Box 1)
      - 1898-1900, 207789 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - 1901-02, 207790 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 1903-05, 207791 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 1906-07, 207792 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - 1908-09, 207793 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - 1910, 207794 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - 1911-12, 207795 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - 1912-13 settlement, 207796 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - 1913 dissolution, 207797 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - 1913 executors, 207798 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - 1913-20, 207799 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - South Texas National Bank, 1890; 207800 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Telegraph code, 1897; 207801 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Resolutions, 1898; 207802 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1890-98; 207803 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Letters of introduction, 1897-98; 207804 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Medical prescriptions, 1897-98; 207805 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Pana, Illinois, 1886-1900; 207806 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Pana, Illinois, 1901-18; 207807 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Pana,Illinois, 1919; 207808 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Americana Brewing Co. indemnity bond, 1896; 207809 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Galveston, LaPorte & Houston Railway Co., 1895-1900; 207810 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Military service record, 1862-65; 207811 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Glenwood Cemetery, 1959; 207812 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Notes receivable, 1895-96; 207813 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Subseries B: Louisa Jones, 207814 (Box 2-4)
    - Correspondence, 207815 (Box 2)
      - Jesse H. Jones, 1906-33; 207816 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Tilford Jones, 207817 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Augusta Jones, 1915; 207818 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Willard [cousin], 207819 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 2908 Main St., Houston, TX, 207820 (Box 2)
      - 1906-10, 207821 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Garden, 1909-15; 207822 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Employees, 1909-13; 207823 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - 1912, 207824 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - 1913, 207825 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - 1914-25, 207826 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Lamar Hotel Apt., Houston, TX, 207827 (Box 2)
      - Household insurance, 1934-35; 207828 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Floor plan, 1926-27; 207829 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Personal property, 207832 (Box 2)
      - Household inventory, n.d.; 207850 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Fire inventory, 1918; 207851 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Italian furniture/ceramics, 1904-05; 207852 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Furniture, 1924-25; 207853 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Furniture, 1953; 207854 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Chickering piano, 1923-24; 207855 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Clothing, 1915; 207856 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Clothing and household, 1905; 207857 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Furs and silver, 1904-31; 207858 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Silver, linen, books, pictures, 207859 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Keys, 1920, 25; 207860 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Automobiles, 207861 (Box 2)
      - 1912 Renault limo, 1919-27; 207862 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Essex and Hudson autos, 1920-32; 207863 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - 1922 Pierce Arrow, 1921-25; 207864 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - 1923 Buick Roadster, 1923-32; 207865 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - 1927 Pierce Arrow, 1927-29; 207866 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - 1930 Pierce Arrow, 207867 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Property trusts, 207868 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Donations: St. Paul's Methodist Church, 1907-14; 207869 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Donations, 1910-29; 207870 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Will, 1899; 207871 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Will, 1925; 207872 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Investments, 207873 (Box 3)
      - Notes receivable, 1902-21; 207874 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Monterrey, Mexico property, 1905-21; 207875 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Notes payable, 1906-20; 207876 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - South Texas National Bank, 1907-08; 207877 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Jones & Jones account, 1910-13; 207878 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Notes payable-Dillingham, 1910-17; 207879 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Union National Bank, 1912-14; 207880 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Bankers Trust Co., 1913; 207881 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Properties listing, 1913, 1921; 207882 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Attorney, 1915-17; 207883 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Notes payable-Sweet, 1915-22; 207884 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Investments, 1915-38; 207885 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Power of Attorney-Bolton, 1916; 207886 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Union National Bank, 1919; 207887 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Oil and gas, 1919-26; 207888 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Notes payable, 1921-32; 207889 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Oil stocks, 1922; 207890 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Bankers Trust Co., 1923; 207891 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Traveler's Insurance, 1930; 207892 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Oil and gas, 1930-32; 207893 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Poll tax, 1930-32; 207894 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Income tax, 207895 (Box 3-4)
      - 1913, 207896 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - 1914, 207897 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - 1915, 207898 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - 1916, 207899 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - 1917, 207900 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - 1918, 207901 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - 1919, 207902 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - 1920, 207903 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - 1920-21 amended, 207904 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 1921, 207905 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - 1922, 207906 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - 1923, 207907 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - 1924, 207908 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - 1925, 207909 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - 1926, 207910 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - 1927, 207911 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - 1928, 207912 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - 1929, 207913 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - 1930, 207914 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - 1931, 207915 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - 1932, 207916 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - 1933, 207917 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - 1934, 207918 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - 1936-37 estate, 207919 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - 1938-39 estate, 207920 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - 1940-41 estate, 207921 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - 1942-44 estate, 207922 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Birchmonte, North Conway, NH, 207923 (Box 4)
      - Property purchase, 1906; 207924 (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - Transfer of property, Augusta Jones to Louisa Jones, 1907-10; 207925 (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - Invoices and receipts, 1907-31; 207926 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - Household insurance, 1921-36; 207927 (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - Electric bills, 1921-30; 207928 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - Tax receipts, 1923-34; 207929 (Box 4, Folder 25)
      - Telephone bills, 1926-30; 207930 (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - Fire insurance, 1933-36; 207931 (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - Caretaker, 1935-36; 207932 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Check registers, 207933 (Box 5, Folder 2-5)
      - Historical information, 207934 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Subseries C: Augusta Jones, 207935 (Box 5-6)
    - Correspondence, 207936 (Box 5)
      - James D. Hunting, 1904-12; 207937 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - George R. Tabor, 1914-15; 207938 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - General, 1920-59; 207939 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Mary G. Locke, 1938; 207940 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - J. Goodwin Locke, 1938-39; 207941 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - A. Jeanntte Jones, 1938-39; 207942 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Catherine L. Evans, 1948-57; 207943 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Lillian Locke, 1953; 207944 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Bernice Runyon, 1953-61; 207945 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Personal property, 207946 (Box 5)
      - Consignment, storage and transfer, 1914-36; 207947 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Hardman grand piano, 1917; 207948 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Furs, 1923; 207949 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Paintings, 1933-49; 207950 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - 1935 Oldsmobile, 207951 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - English chairs, 1937; 207952 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - Lamar Hotel apt. contents, 1960; 207953 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Los Angeles, CA real estate, 1927-46; 207954 (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - Notes receivable, 1903-61; 207961 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Women's Building of Houston membership, 1942; 207955 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Donations, 1953; 207956 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Wills, 1955-56; 207957 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Powers of Attorney, 1915-33; 207962 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Estate, 1960; 207958 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Insurance, 207959 (Box 6)
      - Homeowners: 1108 Bartlett, Houston, TX, 1935-40; 207960 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Life: Pennsylvania Mutual, 1906-18; 207964 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Life: Southwestern Life, 1906-32; 207965 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Life: Southwestern Life #9653, 1906-32; 207966 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Life: Southwestern Life #9654, 207967 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Life: Southwestern Life #9655, 207968 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Life: Southwestern Life #9656, 207969 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Life: Equitable Life Assurance Society, 1911-15; 207970 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Travel, 1928; 207971 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Taxes, 207972 (Box 6)
      - Los Angeles, CA, 1926-32; 207973 (Box 6)
        - 1926-32, 207976 (Box 6, Folder 10)
        - 1933-36, 207977 (Box 6, Folder 11)
        - 1937-41, 207978 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Income, 207979 (Box 6-7)
        - 1913-17, 207980 (Box 6, Folder 13)
        - 1921-22, 207981 (Box 6, Folder 14)
        - 1923-24, 207982 (Box 6, Folder 15)
        - 1925-26, 207983 (Box 6, Folder 16)
        - 1927-28, 207984 (Box 6, Folder 17)
        - 1929-30, 207985 (Box 6, Folder 18)
        - 1931-32, 207987 (Box 6, Folder 19)
        - 1933-34, 207988 (Box 6, Folder 20)
        - 1935-36, 207989 (Box 6, Folder 21)
        - 1937-39, 207990 (Box 6, Folder 22)
        - 1940-42, 207991 (Box 7, Folder 1)
        - 1943-44, 207992 (Box 7, Folder 2)
        - 1945-46, 207993 (Box 7, Folder 3)
        - 1947-48, 207994 (Box 7, Folder 4)
        - 1949-50, 207995 (Box 7, Folder 5)
        - 1951-52, 207996 (Box 7, Folder 6)
        - 1953-54, 207997 (Box 7, Folder 7)
        - 1955-56, 207998 (Box 7, Folder 8)
        - 1957-58, 207999 (Box 7, Folder 9)
        - 1959, 208000 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Subseries D: W.E. Jones, 208001 (Box 7-9)
    - Deepwater, 208002 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Deepwater claim, 1898; 208003 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - New York trip, 1905; 208004 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Notes payable, 1893-1925; 208005 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Notes receivable, 1905-20; 208008 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Expenses, 1893-1924; 208009 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - M.T. Jones estate, 1905, 1912; 208010 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Houston Country Club, 1906-20; 208011 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 208012 (Box 7)
      - 1919-20, 208013 (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - M.T. Jones, 1897; 208014 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Check registers, 1910-11; 208015 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Lodge-Tarpon, TX, 1913; 208016 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Pesonal property, 208017 (Box 7-8)
      - Pierce Arrow, 1909; 208018 (Box 7, Folder 23)
      - 1912 Waverly Electric, 1912-19; 208019 (Box 7, Folder 24)
      - 1914 Stearns-Knight Roadmaster, 1914-17; 208020 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Boat-Hard Times, 1910-11; 208021 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Boat-Grey Fox, 1911-15; 208022 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Legal, 208023 (Box 8)
      - General, 1918-20; 208024 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Investments, 1910-19; 208025 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Power of Attorney-Heyne, 1923; 208026 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Power of Attorney-M.T. Jones, 1924; 208027 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Will, 1935; 208028 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Trust estate, 208029 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Income Tax, 208030 (Box 8)
      - 1913-14, 208031 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - 1915-16, 208032 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - 1917-18, 208033 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - 1919-20, 208034 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - 1921-22, 208035 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - 1923-24, 208036 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - 1925-26, 208037 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - 1927-28, 208038 (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - 1929-30, 208039 (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - 1931-32, 208040 (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - 1933-34, 208041 (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - 1935-36, 208042 (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - 1937-38, 208043 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Insurance, 208044 (Box 8-9)
      - Life, 208045 (Box 8)
        - American National, 1908-10; 208047 (Box 8, Folder 23)
        - Knights of the Macabees, 1908-10; 208048 (Box 8, Folder 24)
        - Aetna, 1911-20; 208049 (Box 8, Folder 25)
        - Great Southern, 1914-37; 208050 (Box 8, Folder 26)
        - Mutual Life NY, 1902-37; 208051 (Box 8, Folder 27)
        - Ocean Accident & Guarantee, 1908-31; 208054 (Box 9, Folder 1)
        - Postal Life, 1915-37; 208055 (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Provident Savings Life Assurance, 1906-11; 208056 (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Travelers, 1903-07; 208057 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Carpet cleaning, 1906; 208058 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Seabrook Hunting and Fishing Club, 1906; 208059 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Subseries E: A. Jeannette Jones, 208060 (Box 9)
    - Pelmanism worksheets, 1920s; 208061 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Pelmanism workbooks, 208062 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - New York trip, 1905; 208063 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Bills and receipts, 208064 (Box 9)
      - General, 1957-59; 208069 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Professional services, 208070 (Box 9)
        - 1925-54, 208071 (Box 9, Folder 11)
        - 1951-55, 208072 (Box 9, Folder 12)
        - 1952-56, 208073 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - Medical bills, 208074 (Box 9-10)
        - Leroy Sanitarium, 1955-56; 208075 (Box 9, Folder 14)
        - 1956-57, 208076 (Box 9, Folder 15)
        - 1958, 208077 (Box 10, Folder 1)
        - 1959, 208078 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Financial, 208079 (Box 10)
      - 1913-16, 208080 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Notes receivable, 1908; 208081 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Madison Operating Corp., 1952-54; 208082 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Investments, 1946-57; 208083 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Accounts, 1952-54; 208102 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Income tax, 208104 (Box 10)
        - 1913-17, 208105 (Box 10, Folder 8)
        - 1918-20, 208106 (Box 10, Folder 9)
        - 1921-23, 208107 (Box 10, Folder 10)
        - 1924-26, 208108 (Box 10, Folder 11)
        - 1927-29, 208109 (Box 10, Folder 12)
        - 1930-32, 208110 (Box 10, Folder 13)
        - 1933-35, 208111 (Box 10, Folder 14)
        - 1936-38, 208112 (Box 10, Folder 15)
        - 1939-41, 208113 (Box 10, Folder 16)
        - 1942-44, 208114 (Box 10, Folder 17)
        - 1945-47, 208115 (Box 10, Folder 18)
        - 1948-50, 208116 (Box 10, Folder 19)
        - 1951-53, 208117 (Box 10, Folder 20)
        - 1954-56, 208118 (Box 10, Folder 21)
        - 1957-59, 208119 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 208084 (Box 10-11)
      - Childer's dispute, 1901-11; 208085 (Box 10, Folder 23)
      - 1901-38, 208086 (Box 10, Folder 24)
      - Jesse H. Jones, 1935, 1956; 208087 (Box 10, Folder 25)
      - 1953-55, 208088 (Box 10, Folder 26)
      - 1956, 208089 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - 1957, 208090 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - 1958, 208091 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Personal property, 208092 (Box 11)
      - 1922 Renault, 1922-25; 208093 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - 300 Park Ave., Apt. 11C, NYC, 1925; 208094 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - 1158 Fifth Ave., Apt. 11C, NYC, 1940-55; 208095 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - 1158 Fifth Ave., Apt. 11D, NYC, 1952-56; 208096 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Mayfair House #15K, NYC, 208097 (Box 11)
        - 1955, 208098 (Box 11, Folder 8)
        - 1957, 208099 (Box 11, Folder 9)
        - 1958, 208100 (Box 11, Folder 10)
        - 1959, 208101 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Legal, 208120 (Box 11)
      - Power of Attorney-Jesse H. Jones, 1915; 208121 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - Trust estate, 1920s-30s; 208122 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Trust estate, 1936-44; 208123 (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - Wills, 1946, 59; 208124 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - Estate correspondence, 1959-60; 208125 (Box 11, Folder 16)
      - Estate settlement, 1959-60; 208126 (Box 11, Folder 17)
      - Estate appraisals, 1960; 208127 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Subseries F: John T. Jones, 208128 (Box 12)
    - Newsclippings, 208129 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 208130 (Box 12)
      - Jesse H. Jones, 1920-33; 208131 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Alfred Smith, 1928; 208132 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Draughon College, Springfield, TN, 1956; 208144 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Personal property, 208133 (Box 12)
      - 1938 Cadillac, 1940-1946; 208134 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - 1940 Oldsmobile, 1940-46; 208135 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - 1941 Plymouth, 1941-42; 208136 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - 3815 Montrose Blvd., Houston, TX, 208137 (Box 12)
        - 1911-19, 208138 (Box 12, Folder 8)
        - 1920-24, 208139 (Box 12, Folder 9)
        - 1925-28, 208140 (Box 12, Folder 10)
        - 1938-55, 208141 (Box 12, Folder 11)
        - 1940-55, 208142 (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - Houston Country Club stock, 1923; 208150 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Financial, 208159 (Box 12)
      - Notes payable, 1905-46; 208160 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Notes receivable, 1923-29; 208161 (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - Bills and receipts, 208162 (Box 12)
        - Worth Hotel, Ft. Worth, TX, 1936; 208163 (Box 12, Folder 16)
        - Lamar Hotel, Houston, TX, 1946; 208164 (Box 12, Folder 17)
        - Rice Hotel, Houston, TX, 1946; 208165 (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - Accounts (Mrs. John T. Jones), 1953; 208166 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Legal, 208167 (Box 12)
      - Power of Attorney-Fred Heyne, 1919; 208168 (Box 12, Folder 20)
      - Power of Attorney-Jesse H. Jones, 1921; 208169 (Box 12, Folder 21)
      - Trust agreements, 1932-46; 208170 (Box 12, Folder 22)
      - Will-John T. Jones, 1937; 208171 (Box 12, Folder 23)
      - Will-Margaret W. Jones, 1937, 47; 208172 (Box 12, Folder 24)
      - Estate, 208173 (Box 12)
        - 1946, 208174 (Box 12, Folder 25)
        - Insurance, 1946; 208175 (Box 12, Folder 26)
        - Insurance trust, 1946; 208176 (Box 12, Folder 27)
        - 1947, 208177 (Box 12, Folder 28)
        - 1948, 208178 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Insurance, 208179 (Box 13)
      - American General, 1946; 208180 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - American National, 208181 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - California Western Life, 1932-46; 208182 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Equitable Life Assurance, 1925-46; 208183 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Franklin Life, 1927-46; 208184 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - General American Life, 1933-46; 208185 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - General American Life, 1938-40; 208186 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Great Southern Life, 1917-46; 208187 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Gulf States Security Life, 1933-37; 208188 (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - Home Life, 1913-45; 208189 (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - Kansas City Life, 1931-45; 208190 (Box 13, Folder 11)
      - Metropolitan Life, 208191 (Box 13, Folder 12)